<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!DOCTYPE xep SYSTEM 'xep.dtd' [
  <!ENTITY % ents SYSTEM 'xep.ent'>
%ents;
]>
<?xml-stylesheet type='text/xsl' href='xep.xsl'?>
<xep>
	<header>
		<title>Tables in Instant Messaging</title>
		<abstract>This specification provides a means to send tables between instant messaging clients, or between robots and instant messaging clients.</abstract>
		&LEGALNOTICE;
		<number>xxxx</number>
		<status>ProtoXEP</status>
		<type>Standards Track</type>
		<sig>Standards</sig>
		<approver>Council</approver>
		<dependencies>
			<spec>XMPP Core</spec>
			<spec>XEP-0001</spec>
		</dependencies>
		<supersedes/>
		<supersededby/>
		<shortname>NOT_YET_ASSIGNED</shortname>
		<author>
			<firstname>Peter</firstname>
			<surname>Waher</surname>
			<email>peter.waher@clayster.com</email>
			<jid>peter.waher@jabber.org</jid>
			<uri>http://www.linkedin.com/in/peterwaher</uri>
		</author>
		<revision>
			<version>0.0.1</version>
			<date>2013-12-11</date>
			<initials>pw</initials>
			<remark>
				<p>First draft.</p>
			</remark>
		</revision>
	</header>
	<section1 topic='Introduction' anchor='intro'>
		<p>
			There are cases where an interchange of tables between internet messaging clients and/or chat robots is desired. Examples include pasting
			tabulated data from the clipboard (perhaps kopied from a spread sheet) or a chat robot presenting data in tabular form.
		</p>
		<p>
			Prior to this extension sending tabulated data could be achieved in various ways:
		</p>
		<ul>
			<li>
				The tabulated data could be sent using a normal text message without formatting, where cells where separated by a tab character (\t). 
				The problem with this approach is that it only works if contents are more or less uniformly spaced. When cell contents cross by the receiver
				preset tabs, the columns are offset a corresponding amount of columns. And since the sender cannot control which font is used to present the
				data, there's no way for the sender to know if data is tabulated correctly on the receiving end or not.
			</li>
			<li>
				The tabulated data could be encoded using HTML and sent according to &xep0071; This works in some clients, but is actually prohibited in ยง5 of
				the same extension. Since support for this is prohibited and extension of the corresponding XEP is not desired, using XHTML-IM to convey
				tabular data is not a recommended option.
			</li>
			<li>
				The tabulated data could be rendered as an image on the sender side, and the image transmitted to the client either using XHTML-IM itself, or
				some other means. The problem with this approach is that the tabular data cannot be used by the received more than to view it. It cannot be 
				edited, saved or used in a spread sheet application, which might have been the original idea.
			</li>
		</ul>
		<p>
			So this extension specifies a means to encode and send tabulated data between XMPP clients. Apart from being easy to single out and render, the
			receiver would also have the benefit of knowing the data is of tabular format, which allows the client to encode it as such when copying the data
			to a clipboard, making it easy to paste it into spread sheets. Using this extension it would be easy to interchange tabular data without having to
			go through the process of saving it in files, transmitting files and separately opening them, which includes trusting file content, scanning them
			with antivirus software, etc.
		</p>
	</section1>
	<section1 topic='Requirements' anchor='reqs'>
		<p>STRONGLY RECOMMENDED.</p>
	</section1>
	<section1 topic='Glossary' anchor='glossary'>
		<p>OPTIONAL.</p>
	</section1>
	<section1 topic='Use Cases' anchor='usecases'>
		<p>STRONGLY RECOMMENDED.</p>
	</section1>
	<section1 topic='Business Rules' anchor='rules'>
		<p>OPTIONAL.</p>
	</section1>
	<section1 topic='Implementation Notes' anchor='impl'>
		<p>OPTIONAL.</p>
	</section1>
	<section1 topic='Accessibility Considerations' anchor='access'>
		<p>OPTIONAL.</p>
	</section1>
	<section1 topic='Internationalization Considerations' anchor='i18n'>
		<p>OPTIONAL.</p>
	</section1>
	<section1 topic='Security Considerations' anchor='security'>
		<p>REQUIRED.</p>
	</section1>
	<section1 topic='IANA Considerations' anchor='iana'>
		<p>REQUIRED.</p>
	</section1>
	<section1 topic='XMPP Registrar Considerations' anchor='registrar'>
		<p>REQUIRED.</p>
	</section1>
	<section1 topic='XML Schema' anchor='schema'>
		<p>REQUIRED for protocol specifications.</p>
	</section1>
</xep>